<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[WebComponents.org]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[A place to discuss and evolve Web Component best-practices]]></description>
        <link>http://webcomponents.org</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 20:34:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://webcomponents.org/podcasts.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 20:34:11 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[35: React & Reactive Elements]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Andrew Rota &amp; Denis Radin talk about the ways you can leverage both Web Components &amp; React.js together in a symbiotic
fashion. Denis, creator of Reactive Elements, starts us off explaining how his library came to be and why he chose to
marry these two technologies in his work. Andrew, who spoke at ReactConf 2015 talks about his experiences with
Web Components &amp; React as well.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/react-and-reactive-elements</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/react-and-reactive-elements</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1096: Web Components with Cory House]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Carl and Richard talk to Cory House about the web component specification and
what that will look like in your modern web development. As Cory explains, the
key idea behind web components is to provide a framework for Javascript library
extensibility that doesn&#39;t force you to own the library yourself.</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->
<p>While the standard is still being discussed, Cory mentions some libraries that
have already gone ahead and implemented a variation of this extensibility, such
as Steve Sanderson&#39;s amazing KnockoutJS. Web components make Javascript that
much better to use!</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/web-components-with-cory-house-on-dotnet-rocks</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/web-components-with-cory-house-on-dotnet-rocks</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[21: The X-Tag Project]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Daniel Buchner talks with The Web Platform Podcast on x-tag, the Custom Elements
library competitor to Polymer, that he created alongside former Mozillian &amp;
Kraken Developer, Arron Schaar.</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->
<p>X-Tag is an interesting way to work with web components in that it takes a
totally imperative approach to creating Web Components as opposed to the
declarative way of building with libraries like Polymer. Some features include
legacy browser support, optional mixins to share across components, &amp; functional
pseudos to assist in delegation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/the-x-tag-project-on-the-web-platform-podcast</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/the-x-tag-project-on-the-web-platform-podcast</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[20: Mozilla Brick, ‘UIKit’ for The Web]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Mozilla Brick contributors Matt Claypotch and Soledad Penades join The Web
Platform Podcast to talk about building UI focused Web Components for &#39;Mobile
First&#39; Web Development.</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->
<p>Mozilla Brick is a set of &#39;Mobile First&#39; focused Web Components built &#39;as close
to the specs as possible&#39;. Brick is not a library built on top of Web Components
like Polymer, Instead, it is a collection of elements with as little abstraction
as possible. Brick&#39;s goal has been to make building the interface of web
applications easier. UI is not as easy for many developers to build from scratch
and it can be difficult to get performant, usable, and attractive widgets.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/mozilla-brick-uikit-for-the-web-on-the-web-platform-podcast</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/mozilla-brick-uikit-for-the-web-on-the-web-platform-podcast</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[141: With Marcy Sutton]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Shop Talk Show is joined by Marcy Sutton. Marcy is an web accessibility expert &amp;
interactive developer at Substantial in Seattle. Chris &amp; Dave take a deep dive
into web components, accessibility, Angular JS, AJAX, ARIA, and more!</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/marcy-sutton-on-shop-talk-show</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/marcy-sutton-on-shop-talk-show</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[14: Web Components Interop and Polymer]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Rob Dodson, Google Engineer, goes through many of the recent changes made to
Polymer, including accessibility and performance enhancements that help in
making applications more integrated.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/web-components-interop-and-polymer-on-the-web-platform-podcast</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/web-components-interop-and-polymer-on-the-web-platform-podcast</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[86: Customizing the Web with Rob Dodson]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Web Components are all the rage these days — a way to create the web using
chunks of code that are reusable across projects. Polymer, a library on top of
web components, is using Web Components today. Rob Dodson joins Jen Simmons in
explaining the current landscape.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/customizing-the-web-with-rob-dodson-on-the-web-ahead</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/customizing-the-web-with-rob-dodson-on-the-web-ahead</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[11: The Bosonic Project]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Raphael Rougeron joins The Web Platform Podscast from Toulouse, France to talk
about The Bosonic Project. Raphael and his team of developers mostly focus their
development efforts working in the Financial Industry, building out secure and
robust applications as well as intricate cross browser UI Components.</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->
<p>The UI components part of Raphael&#39;s work is especially interesting in that it
led him to create The Bosonic Project, an alternative type of Web Components
library that takes a far different approach than Polymer or x-Tag.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/the-bosonic-project-on-the-web-platform-podcast</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/the-bosonic-project-on-the-web-platform-podcast</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9: Web Accessibility for JavaScript Components and Custom Elements]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Steve Faulkner and Marcy Sutton discuss the lack of focus in development today
with regards to building accessible applications &amp; services. Many times web
accessibility becomes an afterthought in creating a software product, having low
prioritization from the business side until it is a real painful problem.</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->
<p>In many client side frameworks there is a growing focus on componentization in
the form of HTML elements. Some examples are Angular Directives, Ember
Components, and React Classes. Web Components, a low level set of native web
technologies, give developers a chance to build better Web Accessibile
components. Using various tools like WAI ARIA roles at a more focused &amp; reusable
level, Web Components may just be the future of accessibility on the web.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/web-accessibility-for-javascript-components-and-custom-elements-on-the-web-platform-podcast</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/web-accessibility-for-javascript-components-and-custom-elements-on-the-web-platform-podcast</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[124: With Rob Dodson]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Shop Talk Show is joined by Rob Dodson. Rob works on Polymer at Google. Chris &amp;
Dave take a deep dive with him into Polymer and Web Components.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/rob-dodson-on-shop-talk-show</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://webcomponents.org/podcasts/rob-dodson-on-shop-talk-show</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>